Inventory of Military Department Records
Connecticut State Library
- Series 2. New Series, 9999-9999
  - U. Fourteenth Connecticut Volunteers
    - Descriptive rolls, recruits (Box 45)
    - Muster rolls (Box 45)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F (Box 45)
      - Companies G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 46)
      - Recruits (Box 46)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 46)
      - Detachments (Box 46)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 47)
    - Descriptive rolls of soldiers (not eligible for mustering out) who were transferred to Second Connecticut Heavy Artillery from Companies A, B, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 47)
  - V. Fifteenth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers (Box 47)
    - Enlistment papers, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H. I, K, Recruits (Box 47)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 47)
    - Company rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, F, G, H, I, K (Box 47)
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 48)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 48)
      - Recruits, 1864-1865 (Box 48)
      - Recruits, 1863-1864 (Box 49)
    - Muster rolls (Box 49)
      - Companies I, K, Field & staff (Box 49)
      - Recruits (Box 49)
    - Monthly returns (Box 49)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls (Box 49)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 49)
      - Recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 49)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 50)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 50)
      - Detachments (Box 50)
  - W. Sixteenth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Enlistment papers (Box 51)
    - Monthly returns (Box 51)
    - Muster in rolls, officers (Box 51)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 51)
    - Muster rolls
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 52)
      - Detachments (Box 53)
      - Field & staff (including Hospital) (Box 53)
    - Muster & Descriptive rolls (Box 53)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Non-commissioned officers staff (Box 53)
      - Recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 53)
      - Recruits transferred from Sixteenth Connecticut Volunteers to Sixth Connecticut Volunteers on muster out of Sixteenth Connecticut Volunteers (Box 53)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 53)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 53)
      - Detachments (Box 53)
  - X. Seventeenth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Enlistment papers, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I (Box 54)
      - 1862 July-August (Box 54)
      - 1864-1865 (Box 54)
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 55)
    - Returns (Box 55)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls (Box 55)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 55)
      - Recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4, 1863-1864 (Box 56)
    - Muster rolls (Box 56)
      - Companies I, K (Box 56)
      - Field & staff (Box 56)
    - Muster in rolls, officers (Box 56)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 56)
      - Detachment (Box 56)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 56)
      - Officers (Box 57)
  - Y. Ninth Connecticut Volunteers
    After the three year tour of duty those veterans who had re-enlisted were formed into the Ninth Battalion consisting of four companies under the command of Captain Healy.
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E (Box 57)
    - Enlistment papers, recruits (Box 57)
    - Muster rolls, Companies F, G, H, I, K. Field & staff (Box 58)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 58)
      - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, B and (Box 58)
      - Muster rolls, recruits (Box 58)
      - Catalogue of recruits (Box 58)
      - Miscellaneous list of soldiers, Company K (Box 58)
      - Roll of married men (Box 58)
      - Letter from Major Bell (?) to Adjutant General of Connecticut (Box 58)
    - Returns (Box 58)
    - Letter from Colonel Cahill at Ships Island, Mississippi regarding Captain Nelson, 1862, February (Box 58)
    - Muster rolls & descriptive lists (Box 59)
      - Companies B, D, E, F, G, I, K, 1862 (Box 59)
      - Recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4, 1864-1865 (Box 59)
      - Veterans, 1864 July 12 (Box 59)
      - Deceased soldiers (Box 59)
    - Muster out rolls, detachments (Box 60)
  - Z. Ninth Battalion
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, Field & staff (Box 60)
    - Returns (Box 60)
    - Detachments (Box 60)
  - AA. Sixth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E (Box 61)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 61)
    - Muster in rolls, officers (Box 61)
    - Muster in rolls, veterans, non-commissioned staffs, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 61)
    - Muster rolls, Companies F, G, H, I, K (Box 62)
    - Descriptive lists, Non-commissioned, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 62)
    - Muster & descriptive lists, non-commissioned, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, veterans (Box 62)
    - Muster rolls, field & staff, recruits (Box 63)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff, officers (Box 63)
    - Muster out rolls, detachments, companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K. non-commissioned, and miscellaneous (Box 63)
    - Enlistment papers, 1863-1864 (Box 63)
    - Muster & descriptive lists, Recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 64)
    - Payrolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 64)
    - Monthly returns (Box 64)
    - Enlistment papers, 1864-1865 (Box 64)
    - Enlistment papers, veterans, Hilton Head, S.C., 1864 (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous letters (Box 64)
      Regarding personnel, transportportation of horses.
    - Original discharge paper, Pvt. Martin Mayer (Box 64)
  - BB. Seventh Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D (Box 65)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 65)
    - Muster in rolls, veterans (Box 65)
    - Muster rolls, Companies E, F, G, H (Box 66)
    - Muster & desciprtive lists, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff (Box 66)
    - Muster rolls, Companies I, K, field & staff, recruits (Box 67)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E (Box 67)
    - Monthly returns (Box 67)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies F, G, H, I, K, field & staff, promotions, detachment (Box 68)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls, recruits (Box 68)
    - Enlistment papers, veterans, 1863 December (Box 68)
    - Enlistment papers, recruits, 1862-1864 (Box 69)
    - Descriptive lists, veterans, recruits (Box 69)
    - Muster in, officers (Box 69)
  - CC. Eighth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, D, E, F (Box 70)
    - Muster in rolls, Enlistment rolls (Box 70)
    - Re-enlistment papers, Companies A, B, C, D, E, G, H, I, K, 1863 December (Box 70)
    - Muster rolls, Companies G, H, I, K, recruits, field & staff (Box 71)
    - Enlistment papers, recruits (Box 71)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, recruits (Box 72)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls, veterans (Box 72)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 72)
    - Monthly returns (Box 72)
    - Muster & descriptive roll, recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4, and Company K (Box 72)
    - Muster out rolls, detachments (Box 72A)
    - Muster & descriptive lists, Company K, recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3 ,4 (Box 72A)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 72B)
  - DD. Tenth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D (Box 72)
    - Muster rolls, Companies E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 73)
    - Returns (Box 73)
    - Muster rolls, recruits, field & staff (Box 74)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, officers (Box 74)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 74)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 74)
    - Muster out rolls, detachments (Box 75)
    - Muster in rolls, descriptive lists, veterans, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, non-commissioned staff, other soldiers (Box 73)
    - Enlistment papers, recruits, 1862-1864 (Box 74)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Band (Box 75)
    - Enlistment papers, recruits, 1864 (Box 72A)
    - Re-enlistment papers, veterans, Cmopanies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, HG, I, K, staff (Box 72B)
    - Enlistment papers, 1864 (Box 72B)
    - Enlistment papers, substitutes (Box 72b)
  - EE. Eleventh Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B (Box 75)
    - Muster in rolls, officers (Box 75)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 75)
    - Muster rolls, Companies C, D, E, F, G (Box 76)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls, Companies B, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff, detachments (Box 76)
    - Muster rolls, Companies H, I, K. field & staff, recruits (Box 77)
    - Muster out rolls, detachments (Box 77)
    - Monthly returns (Box 77)
    - Recruiting return, 1863 December; 1 document (Box 77)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff, officers (Box 78)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 78)
    - Enlistment papers, 1864 (Box 78)
    - Enlistment papers, 1864 (Box 79)
    - Discharge paper, John H. Flint (Box 79)
  - FF. Twelfth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D (Box 79)
    - Muster rolls, Companies E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff, recruits (Box 80)
    - Enlistment papers, recruits (Box 80)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff, officers, detachments (Box 81)
    - Muster & descriptive lsits of veterans, recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4, 1863-1864 (Box 81)
    - Monthly returns (Box 81)
    - Muster in rolls, officers (Box 81)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 81, Folder 157)
    - Muster & descriptive lsits of recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4, 1864 (Box 82)
  - GG. Twelfth Battalion
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, field & staff (Box 82)
    - Muster & descriptive lsits of men transferred from Twelfth Regiment to Twelfth Battalion (Box 82)
  - HH. Thirteenth Regiment
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B (Box 82)
    - Monthly returns (Box 82)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff (Box 82)
    - Muster rolls, Companies C, D, E, F, G, H, I (Box 83)
    - Enlistment papers, recruits (Box 83)
    - Muster rolls, Company K, field & staff, recruits (Box 84)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff, detachments (Box 84)
    - Enlistment papers, veterans, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Band (Box 84)
    - Enlistment papers, veterans, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Band (Box 84)
    - Muster & descriptive lists, recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4, 1863, 1864 (Box 85)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 85)
      - Certificates of enlistment for John Donelly and Hiram Blackman (Box 85)
      - Return of Regimental Inspector of rifle practice (Box 85)
      - Returns of elections of officers (Box 85)
      - Memos regarding commencing recruiting (Box 85)
    - Enlistment papers, Companies A, B, C (Box 85)
    - Enlistment papers, Companies G, H, I, K (Box 86)
  - II. Thirteenth Battalion
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, field & staff (Box 85)
    - Muster out roll, officers (Box 85)
    - Muster & descriptive roll of men transferred from Thirteenth Regiment to Thirteenth Battalion (Box 86)
  - JJ. Third Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff (Box 86)
    - Bounty payments, 2nd & 3rd months, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, staff (Box 86)
    - Payroll, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, field & staff (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 86)
      - Muster out roll of Dr. J. McGregor (Box 86)
      - Returns of officers (Box 86)
      - Tender of service (Box 86)
  - KK. Twenty-seventh & Twenty-eighth Connecticut Volunteers
    - Original discharge papers (Box 72B)
  - LL. U.S. Army units, lists of Connecticut soldiers
    - U.S. Thrid Regiment Artillery (Box 72B)
    - U.S. Fourteenth Regiment Infantry (Box 72B)
    - U.S. Seventeenth Regiment Infantry (Box 72B)
  - MM. Twenty-ninth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers (Colored)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 15)